<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Lab 02 - CodeIgniter Intro
-->
<lab status="beta">
    <!-- Activity metadata ... override anything from the course or organizer -->
    
    <!-- The meat of the presentation -->
    <slide title="Lab Goals" layout="normal">
        <p>The purpose of this lab is to introduce you to
            CodeIgniter and the workflow for working with
            webapps.</p>
        <p>There are three tutorials to complete, for a passing grade, and then 
            this optional lab exercise to complete for potentially full
            marks.</p>
        <p>Suggestion: you may want to skim the slideshow first,
            before working your way through it.</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Lab Submission" layout="normal">
        <p>Your lab will be completed in a github repository.
        If you are just doing the tutorial part of the lab, this
        will be your (forked) tutorial 2c repo. If you are doing the optional
        part of the lab, this will be your (non-forked) converted
            static site repo.</p>
        <p>Dayschool students: submit a readme to the lab dropbox. 
            This readme should have a link to your github repository.</p>
        <p>Distance students: send me an email with a link to your github repository.</p>
        <p>Due: Sunday, Jan 18, 17:30 PST</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Lab Marking Guideline" layout="normal">
        <p>This lab will be marked out of 10, as follows:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Tutorial 02a: add your name to the student list (2)</li>
            <li>Tutorial 02c: convert the image gallery to a CodeIgniter
            webapp (5)</li>
            <li>(Optional) Convert one of the designated static websites to a
            CodeIgniter webapp (3)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Tutorial 2b is not for any marks.</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Lab Preparation" layout="normal">
        <p>Three tutorials have been provided, to setup your development
            environment. Please make sure you have completed them.</p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                <a href="/show/tutorial/02a" target="_blank">Tutorial 02a</a>
            Working With a Shared Repository</li>
            <li>
                <a href="/show/tutorial/02b" target="_blank">Tutorial 02b</a>
            Setup CodeIgniter</li>
            <li>
                <a href="/show/tutorial/02c" target="_blank">Tutorial 02c</a>
            Convert Static Site to CodeIgniter</li>
        </ul>

    </slide>

    <slide title="Disclaimer" layout="normal">
        <p>We will not necessarily be following "best practices" throughout this lab.</p>
        <p>Our focus is on "baby steps", that will lead to best practices over the
            next few labs.</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Post Tutorial Notes" layout="normal">
        <p>If you have completed the week 2 tutorials, you have a "system3" folder
        inside "XAMPP_PATH/htdocs", and you have an idea how to convert a static
        website into a CodeIgniter webapp.</p>
        <p>If you are happy with a passing grade, or if you are out of time, 
        submit your tutorial 2c repo link. If you are shooting for the highest
        possible grade, or if you want to practice the conversion process,
        then continue with this lab.</p>
        <p>Note: You can always submit a link to the tutorial repo once you 
            complete it, and then override your submission if you complete
            the optional part of this lab!</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Eligible Static Sites" layout="normal">
        <p>Here are six free sample websites from 
            <a href="http://www.freewebsitetemplates.com/">Free Website 
                Templates</a> that suit our purposes.
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="http://www.freewebsitetemplates.com/download/hairstylesalon/">Hairstyle Salon</a></li>
            <li><a href="http://www.freewebsitetemplates.com/download/lawfirm/">Law Firm Office</a></li>
            <li><a href="http://www.freewebsitetemplates.com/download/beachresort/">Beach Resort</a></li>
            <li><a href="http://www.freewebsitetemplates.com/download/gardenwalkthrough/">Garden Walkthrough</a></li>
            <li><a href="http://www.freewebsitetemplates.com/download/woodworkingwebsitetemplate/">Wood Working</a></li>
            <li><a href="http://www.freewebsitetemplates.com/download/zerotype/">Zerotype</a></li>
        </ul>
    </slide>

   <slide title="Conversion Process" layout="normal">
       <p>Pick one of the designated sites from the previous slide, and
       make it into a CodeIgniter webapp.</p>
       <p>I suggest following the lead of the CodeIgniter conversion
       project, used in Tutorial 2c.</p>
       <p>Create a new project for your webapp, extract the free website 
           into the "public" folder inside your lab 2 project, and
           then perform the same activites that you did for 
           tutorial 2c :)</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Are We There Yet?" layout="normal">
        <p>When you are done, you will submit either the link to your
        tutorial 2c repository, *or* the link to your converted
        free website template.</p>
        <p>In either case, working through the tutorial or converting
        one of the other static sites, please ask questions
        if you get stuck!</p>
    </slide>

</lab>
