<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Normal 01 - Working With Controllers & Routing
-->
<tutorial status="beta">
    <!-- Activity metadata ... override anything from the course or organizer -->
    
    <!-- The meat of the presentation -->
    <slide title="Tutorial Goals" layout="normal">
        <p>This tutorial will walk you through some common controller and
            routing challenges.</p>
        <p>The goal is to fix the broken starter webapp, as directed.</p>
        <p>That can't be so hard, can it? &lt;-- said with a straight face.</p>
        <p>Suggestion: you may want to skim the slideshow first,
            before working your way through it.</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Preparation" layout="normal">
        <div class="left">
            <p>I have prepared a 
                <a href="https://github.com/comp4711/starter-lab03">
                    starter webapp</a> – a mini 
                "content management system". 
                It is incomplete and the pieces are not properly connected, 
                and you need to fix these, as described following.</p>
            <p>Fork the github project, and clone it locally to
                work with, the same as you have done with the previous tutorial.</p>
            <p>
                <strong>DO NOT start working with the repository until directed to do so in the tutorial.</strong>
            </p>
        </div>
        <div class="right">
            <br/>
            <img class="scale" width="600" height="312" src="/data/tutorials/pix/3-1.png"/>
        </div>
    </slide>

    <slide title="The Starter Webapp" layout="normal">
        <p>The "Quotes" starter webapp
            uses bootstrap and jquery, 
            simply because they make it so easy to have a 
            not-ugly-though-the-same-as-everyones looking site.</p>
        <p>The  Quotes webapp looks beautiful, I have to admit, but none 
            of the links work, apart from the logo taking you back 
            to the homepage :(</p>
        <p>Your job is to fix these broken links, per the directions that follow :)</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Where Do I Start?" layout="normal">
        <p>There is a view template in <code>application/views/justone.php</code>. 
            This is meant to display just a single quote. 
            Each of the broken links needs to resolve to the appropriate 
            controller, or method in a controller, which extracts the 
            relevant quote from the model, 
            and builds the view parameters for <code>justone</code> to present it.</p>
        <p>Solve the logic for the first broken link that you fix, 
            and you can re-use the technique for all the others.</p>
        <p>The logic? Inside the appropriate method of the appropriate controller,
            the handling of a request should be to retrieve the appropriate
            record from the <code>quotes</code> model, add its fields to the appropriate
            elements of the <code>$this-&gt;data</code> parameter array, and then call
            your inherited <code>render</code> method.</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="What Needs Fixing?" layout="normal">
        <p>You might use the table below as a checklist.
            The next few slides provide helpful details.
        </p>
        <table style="font-size:80%; padding: 10px; text-align:left">
            <tr>
                <th>Link</th>
                <th>Location</th>
                <th>How to Fix It</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>first</td>
                <td>Navbar</td>
                <td>A suitable <b>new controller</b> in controllers/</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>last</td>
                <td>Navbar</td>
                <td>A suitable <b>new controller</b> in controllers/last/</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>sleep</td>
                <td>Homepage</td>
                <td>Remapped to first::zzz, i.e. the "zzz" method inside the "First" controller</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>lock/em/up</td>
                <td>Homepage</td>
                <td>Remapped to welcome::shucks, using wildcard (lock / *), i.e. the "shucks"
                    method inside the "Welcome" controller</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>show/3</td>
                <td>Homepage</td>
                <td>Remapped to first::gimme/3, using wildcard (show / digit),
                    i.e. the "gimme" method inside the "First" controller,
                    with that method defined to take a parameter</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>dunno</td>
                <td>Homepage</td>
                <td>Remapped to guess (<b>new controller</b>)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>wise/bingo</td>
                <td>Homepage</td>
                <td>Remapped to bingo, using regular expression 
                    (4 letters / bingo) (<b>new controller</b>)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>comp4711/wisdom</td>
                <td>Homepage</td>
                <td>Remapped to bingo::wisdom, using regular expression (comp + digits / *)</td>
            </tr>
        </table>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Suggested Process" layout="normal">
        <p>Fix the problems in sequence, working your way down the table.</p>
        <p>For each of these, I suggest you determine the controller 
            responsible for handling the request, the method inside 
            that controller, and then the necessary routing.</p>   
        <p>Note that the table row for "last" suggests a controller 
            in <code>controllers/last/</code> ... 
            this explicitly means that "last" is a subfolder 
            inside <code>application/controllers</code>. Hmmm.</p>         
    </slide>

    <slide title="Helpful Hint" layout="normal">
        <p>A helpful hint... if you retrieve a record from your model, 
            and you want to add its key/value pairs to the view 
            parameters array, you could have a bunch of assignments 
            (<code>$this-&gt;data['who']= ...</code>), 
            but there is an easier way:</p>
        <p>
            <code>$record = $this-&gt;quotes-&gt;whatever(...);<br/>
                $this-&gt;data = array_merge($this-&gt;data, $record);</code>
        </p>
        <p>The above references a "whatever" method inside your "quotes"
            object, which comes from autoloading <code>application/models/Quote.php</code>.</p>
        <p>
            <code>array_merge</code> is a function built-in to PHP, which merges
            an associative array (the second parameter) into another (the first parameter),
            and returns the merged resulting associative array.
        </p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Let's Get Started" layout="normal">
        <p>Inside your IDE, create a new branch, "develop",
            based on "master". </p>
        <p>This protects you if there are any
            updates to the starter repository, which you would then merge
            into your "master" branch. If this happens,
            you might have to resolve any resulting conflicts in your "develop" and
            derivative branches, but it will be loads easier if
            you have separated the master and develop branches this way.</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Fix the Broken Links Now" layout="normal">
        <p>Fix each of the broken links, one at a time.</p>
        <p>You can choose to create a feature branch for each of these,
            merging them into your "develop" branch once working, or you could
            group the changes needed to fix a link into a single commit,
            to your "develop" branch.</p>
        <p>The first way, you will end up with eight branches: master, develop,
            and then one for each fixed link. The second way, you will end up with two branches,
            master and develop.</p>
        <p>After fixing each broken link, commit your changes and push them to your 
            "origin". If you are using feature branches for each fix, merge
            your working branch into "develop", so that subsequent fix/feature
            branches can be based on the most recent "develop" branch.</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Are We Done Yet?" layout="normal">
        <p>When you are done, nothing will look different on the homepage, but
            the links will work properly :)</p>
        <p>Merge your "develop" branch" into your "master" now.</p>
    </slide>

</tutorial>
