<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Tutorial 07 - Processing XML
-->
<tutorial status="beta">
    <!-- Activity metadata ... override anything from the course or organizer -->
    
    <!-- The meat of the presentation -->
    <slide title="Tutorial Goals" layout="normal">
        <p>This tutorial is meant to give you some exposure to working with
            SimpleXML to process an XML document.</p>
        <p>I have prepared an example project for you to build on.
            It is a webapp, meant  to process
            the XML data you built last lab.</p>
    </slide>

    <slide>
        <h1>Revisions &amp; Notes</h1>    
        <ul>
            <li></li>
        </ul>            
    </slide>
    
    <slide title="Background" layout="normal">
        <p>Barker Bob, with his Burger Bar, wants to hold a bigger,
            better, burger bonanza, in honour of his uncle Billy Bob.</p>
        <p>Last week, you devised a suitable DTD for constraining
            orders, and that resulted in some test data.</p>
        <p>Your job this week is to present a summary of orders and
            and print out a receipt for a selected one.</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="Preparation" layout="normal">
        <p>I have prepared a 
            <a href="https://github.com/comp4711/example-simplexml" target="_blank">
                example project</a>. </p>
        <p>We are using the same menu as last week, and its data is inside
            the menu.xml file inside the data folder.</p>
        <p>Fork the github project, and clone it locally to
            work with, the same as you have done with the previous tutorials.</p>
        <p>Don't forget to add the special order you made last week, 
            to the data folder!</p>
    </slide>

    <slide title="The End Result" layout="normal">
        <p>Your webapp is a two-page one: the home page presents a list
            of the orders found in the data folder, and the order page should print out
            the details for the selected order.</p>
        <p>There shall be <strong>no PHP in your views</strong>. You are welcome to add
            view fragments as you deem fit.</p>
        <p>There shall be <strong>no SimpleXML in your controllers</strong>.
            You are welcome to add models or model methods, as you deem fit.</p>
    </slide>

 
    <slide title="WHAT'S WHERE?" layout="normal" tag="tag1">
        <div class="left">
            <p>Some general stuff:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>A couple of constants are defined in config/constants.php</li>
                <li>A simple base controller is there: core/MY_Controller.php</li>
                <li>We have a master view template, views/_template.php</li>
            </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="right">
            <p>Some familiar stuff:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>View templates for an order (views/aburger.php)
                    and for an order with several burgers, (views/justone.php)</li>
                <li>A homepage view, showing a list of orders, views/homepage.php)</li>
            </ul>
        </div>
    </slide>

    <slide title="WHAT'S WHERE?" layout="normal" tag="tag1">
        <div class="left">
            <p>The important stuff:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Our one-page controller, controllers/Welcome.php </li>
                <li>Our models, models/Menu.php and models/Order.php</li>
            </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="right">
            <p>The data?:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>/data/menu.xml </li>
                <li>/data/order#.xml, each of these storing a single order.</li>
            </ul>
        </div>
    </slide>


</tutorial>
